<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrick&#39;s Engineering Blog</title>
    <link>http://patrick.engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Patrick&#39;s Engineering Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 08:30:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://patrick.engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL: 3 Things to Know About UPDATE Statements</title>
      <link>http://patrick.engineering/posts/postgres-internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 08:30:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrick.engineering/posts/postgres-internals/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading PostgreSQL 14 Internals by Egor Rogov. This book might be the best PostgreSQL resource besides the official documentation. I consider it one of the rare books that teach applied computer science without watering down the difficult parts.
One particularly interesting topic is PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s execution of UPDATE statements. Updates in relational databases are naturally complex. They can be affected by conflicts, anomalies, and deadlocks. However, some behavior is specific to PostgreSQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professionalism in Software Engineering</title>
      <link>http://patrick.engineering/posts/professionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 17:55:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrick.engineering/posts/professionalism/</guid>
      <description>Having worked as a software engineer for a few years, it turns out software engineering is a profession like many others: you are part of a team with fellow humans, and working to achieve something in a collaborative fashion.
I find it important that we enjoy working with each other. I would like to be a reliable, cooperative, and helpful coworker. In short, I would like to be a professional (but never boring) version of myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Your API on AWS Free Tier — A Step-By-Step Guide</title>
      <link>http://patrick.engineering/posts/aws-eb-production-setup-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 18:03:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrick.engineering/posts/aws-eb-production-setup-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I was trying to deploy a backend API for my favorite party game Ryggio on Amazon Web Services (AWS). To my surprise, a comprehensive1 deployment guide was missing—which motivated this attempt to create one.
This guide attempts to include everything for your API to be production-ready, including:
 Basic configuration of Amazon Elastic Beanstalk How to use a custom domain Securing your API using TLS encryption (HTTPS)  The best of all this: Apart from the domain, you can get all of this for free2 using AWS Free Tier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Actually Like Slack</title>
      <link>http://patrick.engineering/posts/slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 20:30:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrick.engineering/posts/slack/</guid>
      <description>As a software engineer, you really need your focus time. Unfortunately, distractions are everywhere! It might be snowing outside, or you might be wondering if now is the perfect time to get a coffee. Then it happens—someone has used Slack&amp;rsquo;s @channel tag to completely interrupt everybody else, including you.
This scenario may sound familiar. The reason is that Slack has given the nuclear codes to everyone in the company, allowing them to destroy productivity with one single command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://patrick.engineering/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 20:37:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrick.engineering/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog and bienvenid@s! I&amp;rsquo;ll publish emotional rants and other random thoughts here every sometimes. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;ll be enjoying the sun for a bit.
Note: This post is not an April Fools&#39; joke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Patrick.</title>
      <link>http://patrick.engineering/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 20:37:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://patrick.engineering/about/</guid>
      <description>I live in Berlin, Germany. I am currently working on chat automation at Charles as a Senior Software Engineer. Previously, I was the Lead Backend Engineer @ Jodel, a German social network. I have a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in computer science from Karlsruhe Institute of Technology.
Apart from drinking tea and reading Hacker News comments, I love to code for fun. Check out Ryggio – made by two friends of mine from Sweden 🇸🇪 and me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
